mail.ee 2018-11-23

# Mail.ee Help

## Confidentiality policy

The confidentiality policy of SIA “INBOKSS”  defines how SIA "INBOKSS" reg. No. 40003560720, hereafter in the text INBOX, uses information and how you, the INBOX user, can protect your confidentiality.

By using INBOX services, you entrust us with your information. This confidentiality policy has been developed to help users understand what information we collect, why we do this, and how we use it. This policy is very important, therefore we hope that you will devote some time to carefully reading this document.

Information management, as well as confidentiality and security protection options are available in the “User Profile” section.

Information provided by you is used to show you the most suitable advertisements, help you to contact people, and provide faster and simpler sharing with others. 

### 1. Collected information

INBOX collects specific information in order to provide users with better services. 

1.1. Personal information

When registering, you must provide information about yourself:

1.1.1  Name

1.1.2  Surname

1.1.3  Birth date

1.1.4  Gender

The information we receive when you use our services. We collect information on what services you use and how you use them. This collection applies to the information below.

1.2. Internet Protocol address

INBOX collects information linked with your login:

1.2.1  Login IP address

1.2.2  Login date and time

1.3. Location information

When you use INBOX services, we can collect and process information on your physical location. INBOX uses location determination technologies based on your IP address. 

1.4. Payment information

When you make a payment for INBOX services, INBOX can collect and process information on your bank account, banking institution, phone number and PayPal account. Payment card information is not collected or processed.

1.5. Local storage

INBOX can process and store information (including personal information) locally on your device, using systems such as your browser’s online storage.

1.6. Cookies and similar technology

When you visit an INBOX service, we (and our partners) use various information collection and storage technologies which can include using cookies or similar technologies for identifying your browser or device. INBOX uses these technologies to collect and store information for the purpose of directing advertising.

### 2. Use of collected information 

The information which INBOX collects from all INBOX services is used to provide, maintain, secure and improve current services; to develop new services; and for the security of INBOX users. Collected information is also used to offer INBOX users personalised content and advertisements.

For all INBOX services where an INBOX account is required, INBOX can use the name, surname and username the INBOX user provided when registering their INBOX profile.

When you contact INBOX, your correspondence is saved to help us solve any problems you may come across. We can use your email address to inform you of our services: for example, to let you know of any future changes or improvements.

The information which INBOX collects using cookies and other technologies is used to improve user experience (for example, if you save your language preferences, you will be able to use our services in your chosen language) and general service quality.

When showing users personalised advertisements, identifiers from cookies or similar technologies are not linked with sensitive categories such as race, religious views, sexual orientation or health condition.

INBOX processes personal information in its servers, which are located in Latvia. 

### 3. Transparency and choice

INBOX’s goal is to clearly state what information is collected by INBOX, so that the user can make a considered choice on the use of their collected information. You can choose to take the further actions mentioned below.

3.1. Using the INBOX profile overview, you can review and control certain information linked with your INBOX account.

3.2. Using the advertising preferences under the INBOX profile overview, the user can edit their preferences for advertisements seen on the INBOX network.

Users can block all cookies in their browser, including cookies linked with INBOX services. However, it is important to note that some INBOX services may not function properly if you disable cookies.

### 4. Access to and updating personal information

Regardless of when you use INBOX services, INBOX’s goal is to provide its users access to their personal information. If this information is incorrect, we try to update or delete it quickly.

INBOX’s goal is to provide its services in such a way as to protect information from accidental or malicious deletion. Therefore, after deleting information from INBOX services, a certain amount of time may pass before spare copies of this data are deleted from our active servers.

4.1. INBOX and users’ shared information

4.1.1. You agree that all data provided by you is used for data processing in the INBOX database.

4.1.2. In the “User Profile” section you have the choice to refuse data processing.

4.1.3. Your data will be saved while you use INBOX services.

4.1.4. You have the right to edit and delete your data, in which case data is saved for as much time as necessary to be certain that the edit or deletion has not been performed by a third party who may have unlawfully accessed your email in your name.

4.1.5. INBOX promises to delete at your request any natural person’s data that you have provided.

4.2. Providing personal identifying information is a prerequisite of using INBOX services, considering that the contents of your emails belong to you, and, in the case of a dispute, you must be able to demonstrate your rights.

4.2.1. In accordance with article 13 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council, you have the right to submit complaints to a supervisory institution.

4.2.2. The user has the right to request a copy of their saved personal data in person at the INBOX office by identifying themselves as a profile owner. The user’s saved data information will be prepared within 2 weeks of receiving the request.

### 5. Procedure for deleting and renewing personal information

Users’ personal data can be deleted in the following cases:

5.1. The user has the right to delete their own personal data by deleting their profile in the “User Profile” section; access to the profile will be blocked and information about the user will be deleted from the INBOX servers within one year.

5.2. Based on the INBOX portal conditions for use, INBOX can delete a user’s personal data by deleting the profile, after which point information about the user will be deleted from the INBOX servers within one year.

The waiting period mentioned above is necessary to prevent unsanctioned actions from third parties using a user’s login details.

During the period mentioned above in points 5.1 and 5.2 in which data will be saved, the user has the right to renew their user profile in person at the INBOX office by identifying themselves as the profile owner. Renewal of personal data takes place no later than two days after the request has been received.

During the period mentioned above in points 5.1 and 5.2 in which data will be saved, the user has the right to delete their user profile in person at the INBOX office by identifying themselves as the profile owner. Deletion of personal data takes place no later than two days after the request has been received. 

### 6. INBOX measures for ensuring the security of personal information

INBOX takes the following steps to secure the INBOX business and its users against unsanctioned access to the information held by INBOX, its modification, publication or deletion.

6.1. The following measures are being taken:

6.1.1. Encryption using a standard SSL.

6.1.2. To access their INBOX account, users are offered two-step verification.

6.1.3. To avoid unauthorised access to the system, INBOX supervises the collected information, its storage and processing, including physical security measures.

6.1.4. Access to personal information can only be gained by INBOX employees; those who perform work for us; and representatives who must know this information to process it at our request, who must comply with strict contractual confidentiality requirements, and who can receive a disciplinary fine or be discharged from their duties if they do not comply with these requirements.

### 7. Services to which this confidentiality policy applies

The INBOX confidentiality policy applies to all services offered by INBOX; however the policy does not apply to those services with a separate confidentiality policy which is not reflected in this confidentiality policy.

The INBOX confidentiality policy does not apply to services offered by other businesses or natural persons, including products or sites which may include INBOX services, or other sites linked with INBOX services.The INBOX confidentiality policy does not apply to procedures implemented by other businesses or organisations who advertise INBOX services and who can use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to send and offer suitable advertisements.

### 8. Adherence to the policy and cooperation with regulatory institutions

INBOX regularly reviews its compliance with this confidentiality policy. On receiving an official written complaint or request for support, we contact the submitter to decide on any further actions. To investigate any complaints regarding transfer of personal information which we cannot solve directly with the person involved, INBOX cooperates with the applicable regulatory institutions including local data protection institutions. 

### 9. Changes

This confidentiality policy may change from time to time. INBOX does not restrict the rights of users in accordance with this confidentiality policy without the user’s explicit permission. All changes to the confidentiality policy will be published on this page and, if they are significant, a special notification will be sent (including those regarding specific services, notifications on changes to the confidentiality policy will be sent by email.)

### 10. Other useful material on confidentiality and security

Other useful information on confidentiality and security is available on the INBOX user support website, including the following resources:

10.1. [How INBOX uses cookies](https://help.mail.ee/?keyword=cookie_usage) 

* * *

If you were unable to find answer for your question, please write to [support@mail.ee](mailto:support@mail.ee)
